Guide to the University Policies Reference collection, 1933-ongoing
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
University Policies Reference collection 1933-ongoing
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. University Archives
1.2 Linear Feet 700 Items
The University Policies Reference Collection contains files of University policy statements, manuals, updates, and news clippings.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The University Policies Reference Collection was compiled by University Archives staff from a variety of sources, including campus mailings.
Collection Overview
The University Policies Reference Collection contains University policy manuals, policy statements, updates, memoranda, and news clippings pertaining to the University’s operating policies and policies affecting student life, and reactions to these policies. See the container list for specific subjects. Materials pertaining to the severe weather policy and other personnel policies will be found in the Office of Human Resources Reference Collection.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Bonfires
College students -- Alcohol use
College students -- Drug use
Duke University -- Regulations
Duke University -- Handbooks, manuals, etc
Honor codes (Higher education)
Smoking
Related Material
Office of Human Resources Reference Collection
Duke University Archives
Duke University. Office of the Registrar. Bulletin of Duke University: Information and Regulations.,
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Alcohol (Box 1)
    - Clippings, 1967- (3 folders)
    - Alcohol Memos, Policy, Miscellaneous
    - Alcohol Policy: On Alcohol at Duke, 2005
    - Alcohol awareness - Duke Health Education, circa 1985
  - Automobile regulations, 1933
  - Bonfires, 1986-
  - Conflict of interest
  - Duke University Policy Manual
    - 1979 (2 folders)
    - Superceded material, 1982-1983 (2 folders)
    - 1987 (2 folders)
    - Superceded material, 1995-1997 (3 folders)
  - Drugs, 1968- (Box 2)
  - General policies and regulations of Duke University [1969], 1970
  - Harassment policy; sexual harassment, 1982-
  - Honor code
    - Clippings
  - Minority and women-owned businesses
  - Pickets, protests and demonstrations
  - Safe driving
  - Smoking
  - Substance abuse